Alexandre TANGUY

Engineering manager

Head of IT technical teams and projects with a network and security engineer background.

- What I (love to) do: management of teams, encouraging excellence, lead by example, being data-driven and customer-oriented.
- What I am not: a software engineer.







Who am I and what am I looking for?

Information technology engineer and manager, 33 years old, living in Bordeaux, France.

After 8 years in the tech field as a network and security engineer, where I learned lots of things and grow up as an engineer and a human being, I understood that I was happier and better leading a team and helping its members to grow.

I seized the opportuny offered by OVHcloud to manage one – and then two – teams of software engineers.

Today, I love this mission and I am eager to continue in a challenging environment with great ambition, to build strong teams and achieve big projects.

Professional experience

Engineering Manager @ OVHcloud (January 2020 - Present)

Team leader of the Network Data squad, composed of the Network Observability and the Network IPAM teams.

- The *Network Observability* team has the mission to design, develop, deploy and maintain internal applications to monitor tens of thousands of network devices:
 - Metrics: 50M+ timeseries / 1M+ datapoint per second
 - Logs: 25M+ log messages per day
 - ICMP requests/packets: 18M+ packets per minute
- The *Network IP Management* team has the mission to design, build and maintain applications to manage (internal and external customers) around 4.5M public IP addresses in 3 RIR (RIPE, ARIN, APNIC)
- Point of contact for other teams and PU about Network observability and IP related topics
- Follow-up on projects and program, estimation of required workload, planification
- Creation of rolling roadmaps with Program managers support over 12 months
- Agile methodology implementation and animation: sprint planning, daily, sprint review, retrospective, etc.

Network Engineer @ OVHcloud (Bordeaux) (Mars 2018 - January 2020)

Member of the Network Design Datacenter team, I was in charge of the vRack product design and projects.

- In charge of the design of network products: vRack, datacenter and (during one year) backbone
- In charge of R&D and deployment on datacenter infrastructure projects: IP failover routed in the vRack, OVHcloud Connect, vRack
- Support of the Network Operations team when issue on the perimeter
- Technologies: BGP, VXLAN, ECMP, Cisco and Arista devices, YAML/JSON

Network and Security Engineer @ Cdiscount (Bordeaux) (December 2015 - Mars 2018) Member of the Security team during 1 year and then moved to the SRE team for 1 year (internal move-up).

- In charge of the network and security infrastructure operations (L3)
- In charge of the improvement and evolution of the network and security infrastructure, working in/with the Security team
- Part of the PCIDSS / SOX compliance and annual certification

 Technologies: Cisco ACI, Checkpoint firewalls, F5 loadbalancers, Citrix Netscaler, RIP/OSPF/VLAN

Network and Security Engineer @ Rothschild & Co (Paris) (February 2015 - November 2015) Member of the Network and Security team, as a project lead of the "IT migration of internal ressources to HP Enterprises", and as Net/Sec engineer.

- In charge of the network and security operations (support of the team lead)
- Point of contact and follow-up of the externalisation project

Network and Security Engineer @ Société Générale (Paris) (January 2013 - February 2015) Member of one of the Network and Security team in charge of FranFinance and La Banque Postale Financement.

- In charge of infrastructure operations (75%)
- In charge of infrastructure improvement and migration projects (25%)

Network and Security Engineer @ Crédit Agricole - CA Technologies & Services (Lyon, internship) (July 2011 - November 2012)
Internship and then "contrat de professionnalisation"

- Assistant of the project lead of the "Migration X25" project
- Network L3 operations

Education and languages

- January 2015: CCNA v2 certification (200-120). Result: 958/1000
- 2012: **TOEIC 940/990**
- 2007 2012: SUPINFO Engineer in IT technologies (french Bac+5 Master II niveau 1)
- June 2007: BAC S specialty mathematics (Baccalauréat Scientifique spécialité Mathématiques)

Activities and interests

- **Hobbies**: reading (sci-fi, fantasy, classical, history), photography, music listening (jazz and electronic)
- Sports: climbing/bouldering, running, cycling, hiking
- **Volunteering**: member of the french Red-Cross (Croix-Rouge française) from 2013 to 2015 as a rescuer (PSE2) and local director